Itchy? Itchy, Sosu. Sosu. Itchy, Sosu.
Uh, hey, Fapta? Are you really sure that your wounds are feeling okay? They look pretty bad.
Hadi, no need to worry. Fapta cannot be hurt. Edge part is fine, Sosu.
Um, there's more to it than just the edge. Oh, Rag, are you worrying about Fapta?
Well, of course. You're injured. Again? Pet me again? Like before, around the horns like I like?
Here? I'm not touching your wound, right? Harder. Scratch me a little harder, Sosu.
Hey, uh, Fapta? So why are you doing all this for me anyway?
Hey, uh, Fapta?
What's wrong?
All the beasts going crazy over the smell of Fapta's blood.
Mayan!
We leave that to Gabaroon and go, Sosu.
Padding is precious, Sosu. But freshness is more important.
Rake's back!
Rake! I'm so glad you're okay!
Um, uh, uh, hey, um, what's that?
I can explain it to you later. The blood is attracting a lot of bugs and stuff.
Let's get inside.
Uh...
Uh, huh?
Fapta?
Riko?
Uh, uh-huh.
Come on, Minya.
Uh, uh!
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh...
What? Is that from the princess? I heard she was immortal, but that seems... I... I just... I guess I had no idea.
This is... This must be the balancing.
Similar, but strange. All of Iru Buru is trying out. This is a first for Katja.
Reg, it must be because we have part of Falfta here.
Hey, what should I do with this? Do you think we should bring it to where Nanachi is?
Wait, well, you... you can't just take it the way it looks right now.
The one who bought your friend? Well, if you show it to him, I think... that would probably make him break.
Huh?
And if he does, I don't know what'll happen to your friend in there.
And... um... sorry. How exactly did you get that?
So long as I keep my promise. She said she'd give anything and gave... this.
What kind of... a promise?
You want me... to... destroy the village?
Falfta wants to, but not possible.
Reg is too kind, so cannot do it, Sosu.
Hadi.
So Falfta need Reg help to get inside, so Reg no have to.
Make it so Falfta can go inside of Mother without trouble.
Reg, you said comes out of hand. You said Tufapta can rewrite Sosu.
But you... you said couldn't use because leaving to search for Haku.
You said next time see Fapta will take me with you.
You said you take Fapta to where they are.
And to Mother...
Hey, now wait!
...want you to take me inside, Chosu.
Hold it! Why are you biting?
Reg, you say if Ken rewrite, you change laws not letting Falfta through.
You do that inside, Sosu.
The incinerator!
It's powerful enough to rewrite the rules of the netherworld.
That's what Nanachi said.
What is it?
Reg can shoot it from his hands!
It can burn up anything!
Falfta told me a long time ago, I said it's possible to tear a hole in the wall.
Well, well...
You were the prince all along.
And to think you actually brought back a piece of the princess!
Seems the village has been thrown into chaos by this new value, which shouldn't even exist.
Oh, Vueko, that looks good on you.
But that thing on your head is actually underwear.
It's for villagers with lots of legs.
The shopkeeper said it could also be used as a hood.
So, you finally came out, huh?
Good. I'm so glad.
I take it you already told these kids about the princess.
I did.
I centered the story on myself, though.
I see.
Riko.
So, do you hate me now?
I don't really know you yet to decide that.
But I do like this village.
After all, there's lots of others like me here.
Even more than when I was an orc living with my own people.
Oh? And how are they like you?
Let's see.
I guess...
Well, Wazukyan, I have to wonder, did you descend this far even knowing you were going past the point of no return?
Yeah.
I mean, that was the kind of trip we were on.
Oh, I see. That's what you're getting at.
I heard from the Sovereign of Dawn.
You know him, right? Bondrewd?
He said that even you cave raiders who made their living in this giant pit,
there's only a handful of humans who will descend to a depth that's impossible to return from.
And you're one of them.
One who, while searching for their own gold, found that the place where the darkness lies is even more valuable.
One whose home is found only in the continuation of their quest, and who could only choose to push forward.
This place is a sanctuary for such types who have nowhere left to go.
And let me tell you, there's not a single villager here who wouldn't do the same thing.
Hadi.
Well, yeah. I found tons of value after ending up here, but my days of challenging the pit harken back to my longing.
There's hardly been a day I don't dream of such things.
Hadi.
Oh, you okay, Riko?
I wonder why that is.
Hey, um, Wazukyan? So I, uh, I'm sorry.
I said I don't really know you yet, but actually, there is one thing I know about you.
No matter what you had to sacrifice or trample over, you wanted your wish to come true.
This village where you stay, the creation of this homeland for those who have nowhere to go,
I don't believe that was truly your wish.
If the golden city you saw really does exist in the Abyss, the sixth layer is still only the entrance.
There's no way you, someone who finds value in that extraordinary quest, would choose to stop at the entrance.
So why? Why are you pretending you've given up on your adventure?
Interesting. In the roughly 150 years since the creation of this village, you're the first to notice.
Still, like the others, I can't leave this place.
We can only live within the boundary. Things don't always work out, you know.
What's the matter, Riko?
Fopta has the wish-granting power of all three Cradles of Desire, the only ones who can use the power of the Cradles.
Um, hey, Wazukyan, could it be that you want me to use the power of the Cradles of Desire?
To make it so that the villagers can go back to adventuring again?
Hmm. How did you come to that conclusion?
I've had something like that happen. Besides, I heard you're someone who does everything he can.
Yes, that's great!
Oh, wow, really? You're... you're not denying it?
Hmm?
Challenging the Abyss again. I've dreamed of that scenario countless times.
But it's not something you should burden someone with.
It's not like that, Mugi. I'm not the one who will choose. These kids will, ultimately.
The choice can only be made by the challengers.
That rumbling.
Now, Riko, Reg, what will you choose?
That's...
That's Chiroemo.
Yeah, Chiroemo!
Damn it. I knew it. Bastard was just buying time.
Hey, boy. That thing has come for the piece of the princess you're holding.
You're coming with me.
I'll distract it! Riko! Head somewhere safe!
Reg!
Ma! I need you to take care of Riko!
Yes! It's turning this way!
Good! It's not very fast! I can outrun it!
But what should I do?
What? Something slimy is...
Look, it's starting now.
W-Why'd you bring me back here?
Hmm?
Because you're quick to give in to despair.
Just stay here and watch.
There's something I want to know.
Or actually...
Want some confirmation on.
What is it?
That huge thing.
Why does it have the same name as the piece of trash you took me in?
Jiroemo?
Iremui made him from signals she received from you.
You're special to her.
Iremui was extremely lonely.
After all, you just kept on brooding.
So one day, he just appeared and said he was one of the three sages.
He can talk.
When the village is in danger, he comes to take out the threat, like some sort of guardian.
But if he gets that piece of fakta, then he's doomed.
Because no matter how big he is, he won't come out of the balance and unscathed.
I told you, he's connected to you.
Rather than being a hollow, he's more like a part of this place.
That thing is the will of the village.
What the...
What's happening to it?
Balancing?
No, it looks like...
It became one with the slimy stuff?
The entrance to the village!
Very good!
You're not gonna let those kids get away, are you?
Something...
Oh, no.
Huh?
The wall is...
The wall's getting buried!
I don't have nowhere left to run!
Okay, since fakta is the embodiment of value, if I let it have some of this, will the balancing stop that thing?
He's wavering.
Being indecisive, that's great!
Listen, boy!
That thing's creation, give back to me!
The balancing won't affect him!
A piece of the princess won't stop him from what he's doing!
He's decided!
You're in danger and we'll try to consume you!
You must run!
Vueco...
Run!
You okay?
That's the first time I've seen you shout like that.
My...
My voice was the one thing.
I had plenty of time to train.
I know you told me to run, but...
But where can I go?
A thin, slimy...
Film?
Whoa, is he trying to cover the entire village?
This is looking bad.
Don't touch it hard!
Vueco!
Oh, crap!
He doesn't care if it gets the villagers too?
Stop it!
No, don't!
No, don't you need that!
No!
I have to do it, don't I?
Fakta will offer everything before our promise.
Fakta will do it, Sosu.
But I do like this village.
That village is Mother.
She fell into despair so deep she lost her voice, Sosu.
Mother's regret, Mother's anger.
Those things must be dispelled.
I don't have the power to change things all on my own.
Okay, there's no one behind him.
It's a clear shot.
From this angle, I'd hit him for sure.
But can doing this really change things for the better?
I don't know.
Well, at this point...
Now, there's no time to hesitate!
Wait!
I... I'm sorry. I couldn't think of any other way.
Fakta is coming, and soon!
I fear things are going to get really bad.
Now until I wake back up after fainting,
find somewhere as safe as you possibly can to hide from her!
After you faint?
Yeah, it's the incinerator.
I pass out after using it.
I still have some time left, a few minutes.
But soon, drowsiness will wash over me.
Can I offer this for a favor?
Until I wake up, will you please keep Riko safe inside?
Because outside is the Abyss's world.
I'm sure you know, but it's far more dangerous out there.
Please!
Of course we'll do what you ask. We would be honored.
But that's a tall order for just us three to pull off.
Oh, Kaja will get more help.
Aduh!
Stand back. You are in the presence of a princess.
Sosu. Reg, you have my thanks.
But Fopta will not forgive villagers.
My siblings and Fopta. You glared at us with hungry eyes.
Fopta will not forgive those eyes, your mouths.
You speak in the same tongue my mother did and spit out prayers.
Fopta will not forgive those mouths.
Fopta will not forgive your forms.
You desecrated my mother to selfishly save your own skins.
Fopta will not forgive your lives, which have continued for too long.
Fopta will not forgive your wishes, your joy, your sorrow, your passions.
Fopta will not let any of that continue.
Fopta will never forgive your existence until you are dust, scraped and disregarded.
Fopta was born, so this will not be forgotten.
You know not how Fopta has longed for this day.
Fopta will allow you no time to prepare.
Fopta will eradicate you.
Do not interfere, Sosu.
Brothers and sisters, your youngest sibling has now returned home, Sosu.
You did a good job supporting mother.
You've done enough.
She's all healed.
It is none other than the immortal princess.
What should Kaja do?
So happy.
And so it begins.
Nah, who's singing?
Miri.
Just now, I was having a strange dream.
And in it, there was a man who seemed like a friend, and I felt I needed him to survive.
I was going along with him on some kind of search.
I, I can't remember what we were looking for.
The people he was with sorta resembled us.
Even though, they didn't really look like us at all.
Eventually, they finally found it.
Their treasure.
And for some reason, I couldn't look away.
I don't know why, but it...
It just felt very, very strange.
Hey you.
What is it?
What's going on?
When?
The time to awaken has come.
Nanachi, this is it.
Starting now, it is no longer a dream.
Thank you.